[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Nobel prize is awarded for which of the following disciplines",
    "1": "Literature, peace and economics",
    "2": "Medicine or Physiology",
    "3": "Chemistry and Physics",
    "4": "All the above",
    "answer": 4,
    "tag": "Basic General Knowledge"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Garampani Sanctuary is located in which of the following places",
    "1": "Junagarh, Gujarat",
    "2": "Kohima, Nagaland",
    "3": "Diphu, Assam",
    "4": "Gangtok, Sikkim",
    "answer": 3,
    "tag": "Basic General Knowledge"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Entomology studies what?",
    "1": "Human beings",
    "2": "Insects",
    "3": "The origin and history of technical and scientific terms",
    "4": "The formation of rocks",
    "answer": 2,
    "tag": "Basic General Knowledge"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Galileo was an astronomer who",
    "1": "Developed the telescope",
    "2": "Discovered four satellites of Jupiter",
    "3": "Discovered that the movement of pendulum produces a regular time measurement",
    "4": "All the above",
    "answer": 2,
    "tag": "Basic General Knowledge"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Sun exposure can bring about an improvement in health because of which of the following reasons",
    "1": "The infrared light kills bacteria in the body",
    "2": "Resistance increases",
    "3": "The pigment cells in the skin get stimulated and produce a healthy tan",
    "4": "The ultraviolet rays convert skin oil into Vitamin D",
    "answer": 4,
    "tag": "Basic General Knowledge"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Who is the father of geometry?",
    "1": "Aristotle",
    "2": "Euclid",
    "3": "Pythagoras",
    "4": "Kepler",
    "answer": 2,
    "tag": "Famous Personalities"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The radioactive element radium was invented by which of the following scientists?",
    "1": "Marie Curie",
    "2": "Benjamin Franklin",
    "3": "Albert Einstein",
    "4": "Isaac Newton",
    "answer": 1,
    "tag": "Inventions"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "In which field is the B.C. Roy Award given?",
    "1": "Environment",
    "2": "Journalism",
    "3": "Medicine",
    "4": "Music",
    "answer": 3,
    "tag": "Honors and Awards"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Who authored the ‘Forbidden Verses’?",
    "1": "D.H. Lawrence",
    "2": "Salman RushDie",
    "3": "Ms. Taslima Nasrin",
    "4": "Abu Nuwas",
    "answer": 4,
    "tag": "Books and Authors"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Who played the role of Jack Sully in Avatar?",
    "1": "D.H. Lawrence",
    "2": "Sam Worthington",
    "3": "Ms. Taslima Nasrin",
    "4": "Abu Nuwas",
    "answer": 2,
    "tag": "Movies"
  }
]
